# **PERSONAL**

Name David Kohlbauer

Email david.kohlbauer@gmail.com

Phone +49 160 9210 48 64

Portfolio https://www.behance.net/DavidKohlbauer

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-kohlbauer-a992608a/

**Languages** Native English, Native German

#### **UX / Product Design / Design Thinking Coach**

I deliver holistic experiences made by people for people by solving problems that matter through creating beautiful and clean interfaces. I am specialized in design systems, product strategy, interaction design (UX/UI). I do my best work when focusing on how to help people solve real problems that make an impact in their daily lives.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **BMW - Munich, Germany**

Aug. 2023 - Present

## **Interaction Designer**

Design Leadership / Design Systems - Guiding a small design team to defining a new design language to lead BMW into the next generation of automotive design. Creating BMW's next gen in-car design system and closing the design gap between all digital touch-points

#### SAP - Munich, Germany

Aug. 2020 - July 2023

#### Senior UX Designer

Enterprise Software / Augmented Reality - Managing a design project from ideation, concept, research, to design for a lighthouse project using augmented reality to revolutionize the sector which has been nearly the same for the last decade by delivering iterative design solutions in a high stake project.

#### **BMW - Munich, Germany**

Aug. 2018 - Juli 2020

#### **UX** Designer

Vehicle Integration / Design Systems - Part of the core design team who defined concept and the design direction of the application. In charge of key app features. Created and distributed the design system amongst dozen of other design teams to ensure quality through design patterns and proper component usage.

## **Adesso - Munich, Germany**

Feb. 2018 - Juli 2018

## **UX/UI** Designer

Worked on multiple concurrent consumer applications made for iOS and Android in a fast-paced environment.

## The Asia - Bangkok, Thailand

Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2017

## **UX/UI** Designer

Responsible for the redesign of a responsive consumer website focusing on travel and lifestyle, with focus on scalability and accessibility.

## **Indy Cloud - Bangkok, Thailand**

Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2016

#### **UX/UI** Designer

Designed a dynamic ERP browser application for SME's in a small start-up company with limited resources.

#### 84GHz - Munich, Germany

Juni 2014 - Oct. 2015

#### **UX/UI** Designer

Designed responsive websites for various customer from small single operations to larger corporations.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Blochererschool - Munich, Germany**

2010 - Feb. 2014

Studied communication design with a focus on advertisement, digital design